James Names Moffet

UX Designer & Researcher

jamesdavidmoffet.comjim@jamesdavidmoffet.comjamesdavidmoffet

James Moffet

335A Harvard St. #10 Cambridge, MA, USA +1.773.354.1500 jim@jamesdavidmoffet.com

Fidelity UXD Team

200 Seaport Boulevard Boston, MA 02210

Dear UXD Team,

I'd like to thank Will Reed and Josephine Holmboe for presenting at the Harvard Graduate School of Design this week.

With 10 years' experience as a UX designer, product manager and entrepreneur, I can translate fluently between business goals and design strategy. During a master's degree at the GSD, I've polished my UX theory and added data science to my skillset.

Over the past year, I have guided Outvote, a mobile campaign app startup, through the iLab accelerator to a successful round of investment as a founder and its director of user experience. I managed an agile of team of freelance designers, researchers and engineers. I also committed front-end and back-end code, designed and delivered investment pitches, sales materials and product demos, and generally fixed whatever needed fixing.

Prior to Harvard, I spent 5 years as a UX and Product Manager for Service Employee's International, where I built a user-centered design and engineering team from the ground up that delivered an on-time, on-budget financial data system that increased net revenue by 10% while reducing billing errors by over 90%.

In between, I lectured and conducted research on user-centered design as a Fulbright Fellow.

I'm interested in learning more about how I might contribute to the UXD team, and I'm excited to speak with you further.

Sincerely,

James Moffet



UX Designer & Researcher

jamesdavidmoffet.com

in jamesdavidmoffet

about

As a designer and researcher, I am obsessed with understanding the human interfaces by which technology delivers us into an alternative future. Yet, I have learned to temper this obsession, harnessing critical theory and a range of user-centered research and organizational engineering techniques to help me find room to redirect established practices by applying user-centered and systems-level thinking to the awesome challenge of improving people's experiences.

education

2016 - 2018

Harvard University Graduate School of Design

Master's degree, Design Technology Studies

SKIIS

Design Research
UI/UX Design
Data Science
Software Engineering
Hardware Engineering
Public Speaking
Project Management
Product Design

work experience

OutVote.io

2017 - 2018 Cambridge, MA, USA Director of User Experience
 In 2017, Outvote acquired my civtech
 startup COMM!T, growing to a team of
 five. I direct an agile team of designers,
 coders and researchers to ensure that
 our product that meets the needs of our
 10 enterprise clients and 1000 users.

Independent Consulting

2016-2018 Cambridge, MA, USA

UXD/UXR Consultant

Collaborated with GoINVO on the MA SNAP web application redesign.
Consulted for City of Boston on FOIA process redesign. Designed open source citizen analytics apps for Cambridge.

MIT Community Innovators Lab

2016 - 2017 Cambridge, MA, USA

- Research Manager

Led a team of 12 researchers, designers and devs conducting field/remote user research on 1,200 grassroots organizing groups. Designed, built and deployed a collaborative mapping tool to help orgs discover each other and connect.

Fulbright Fellow

2015 - 2016 Budapest, HU

Lecturer and Researcher

Lectured on design at CEU and piloted OpenLab public design workshops, mentoring UXR, interface design and service prototyping for public projects.

SEIU

2009 - 2014 Portland, OR, USA

Senior UX and Product Manager

Built a user-centered design and engineering team from the ground up, replacing 20-plus-yr-old software products handling all billing and member data. Increased net revenue by 10%, while reducing billing errors by 90%.